BEN BUSSELL

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- **J** 574-265-5037
- benbussell@gmail.com
- benbussell.com
- in linkedin.com/in/benbussell

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts

Indiana University
Bloomington, Indiana | 2006

SKILLS

HTML, Css, JavaScript, GIT, JQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Copywriting, Creative Problem Solving, Content Writing, Creative Thinking, Artistic Design, Team Leading, Event Planning, Storytelling

LANGUAGES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, jQuery, Git, AngularJS, Bootstrap

PROFILE

Driven, creative web designer specializing in front-end development seeks new opportunity. Motivated self-taught candidate experienced in all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well versed in programming languages including HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Over 10 years experience in commercial art and design.

EXPERIENCE

INTERNSHIP

CASPER SECURITY | LOUISVILLE, KY | 2018 - PRESENT

 Utilizes AngularJS and Python to complete tickets for front-end and back-end web development teams

WEB DEVELOPMENT STUDENT

CODE LOUISVILLE | LOUISVILLE, KY | 2018 - PRESENT

- Completed 12 week front-end development course, and enrolled in 12 week back-end development course
- Completed required coursework for front-end course weeks ahead of schedule

SENIOR ART CATALOGER/ CONTENT WRITER

EVERYTHING BUT THE HOUSE | LOUISVILLE, KY | 2016 - 2018

- Maximizes auction results by writing copy describing high value artwork in appealing, informative, and concise manner, using company style and language, optimizes individual item value by researching and composing short biographies for relevant artists
- Edits team members' copy for grammatical errors, factual inaccuracies, and style discrepancies prior to publishing
- Uses web-based resources to research and accurately identify and validate client claims of worth and provenance
- Creates and presents educational training resources for the extended team

BEN BUSSELL

WEB DEVELOPER

CERTIFICATIONS

Code Louisville

May 2018 - July 2018

AFFILIATIONS

Louisville Public Media,

Sustaining Member

Filson Historical Society,

Individual Member

Beechmont Neighborhood Assoc.,

Member

INTERESTS

I co-host a weekly music podcast, "1001 Album Club"

I have a rudimentary print shop in my basement, where I create woodcut relief prints

I love camping and hiking as often as weather and schedule permits

I enjoy puzzles- crossword, sudoku, jigsaw, etc.

I am an accomplished musician and I enjoy performing with friends

I am proud of my diverse record collection, which spans various genres of music from the 1950's to current

EXPERIENCE (continued...)

ASSISTANT PRODUCTION MANAGER

LIVE NATION, LOUISVILLE PALACE | LOUISVILLE, KY | 2016 - 2017

- Assists with managing direct labor budget of event production, marketing, union stagehands, and hospitality
- Collaborates in advance and on day of show with talent management to accommodate all artist requirements and special requests while remaining within a preset budget

TOUR MANAGER

INTERNATIONAL PERFORMING ARTISTS | WORLDWIDE | 2011 - 2016.

- Solely responsible for day to day small business operations while traveling, including scheduling, accommodations, crew supervision, contract fulfillment, and daily financial sales reports averaging \$12K/week
- Acts as daily liaison between management company, record label, and performing artist

SALES ASSOCIATE

THREE SEVEN MARKETING | LOUISVILLE, KY | 2011 - 2012

- Achieved a national, company-wide high sales record for week of March 19, 2012.
- Promoted to team leader, trained new hires in relevant sales skills and strategies
- Created and administered educational presentations and exercises for local sales team

VISUAL ARTIST AND DESIGNER

FREELANCE | NATIONWIDE | 2004 - PRESENT

- Designs and executes creative visual artwork for national and international markets
- Artwork has been used on internationally distributed rock albums,
 merchandise and promotional posters for national tour campaigns
- Established and maintain working relationships with demanding clients that span over 12 years